Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 5 and District 5 Locals, 1936-1983 UE.4.1.5
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- District 5, 1.
  - District 5 General Outgoing Correspondence, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - William Walsh to Julius Emspak Regarding Local 504, March 12, 1953; 1.
    - Bob Ward to William Chan Regarding Political Action, May 14, 1949; 2.
    - Ward to James Matles Regarding Inter-union Rivalry, March 17, 1953; 3.
    - John Wigdor to Ruth Young Regarding Labor Education, January 30, 1945; 4.
    - Wigdor to Emspak Regarding Veterans, June 6, 1945; 5.
    - Idele Wilson to Ed Matthews Regarding Westinghouse and Wages, April 29, 1945; 6.
    - Wilson to Matthews Regarding Wages, Women, and Westinghouse, September 14, 1945; 7.
    - Wilson to Joseph Dermody Regarding White Collar Workers Organization, November 19, 1948; 8.
    - Wilson to Janet Barish Regarding Fringe Benefits, January 7, 1949; 9.
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1954 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, May 1956 - November 1977 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1964 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1966 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1968 - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1969 - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1971 - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1976 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - District 5 General Correspondance, 1980 - 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - District 5 Salary/Expense Letters, 1939-1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - C.S. Jackson, April 3, 1939; 1.
    - Jackson, July 2, 1940; 2.
    - Buell Andress, December 26, 1940; 3.
    - George Harris, July 28, 1941; 4.
    - William Dickson, July 28, 1941; 5.
    - Andress, July 28, 1941; 6.
    - Dickson, August 22, 1941; 7.
    - Harris, August 22, 1941; 8.
    - Harris, September 19, 1941; 9.
    - Averil Arrowsmith, October 6, 1941; 10.
    - Arrowsmith, October 9, 1941; 11.
    - Andress, November 18, 1941; 12.
    - A.C. Avery, November 18, 1941; 13.
    - Arthur Hastings, December 5, 1941; 14.
    - Arrowsmith, January 9, 1942; 15.
    - Jackson, September 22, 1942; 16.
    - Jackson, October 1, 1942; 17.
    - Jackson, October 5, 1942; 18.
    - Jackson, December 1, 1942; 19.
  - District 5 Receipts, November 24, 1937-March 9, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - District 5 Financial Statements, March 5, 1938-September 30, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - District 5 Officer's Research Reports, 1957 - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - District 5 Officer's Research Reports, 1964 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - District 5 Officer's Research Reports, 1971 - 1972, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - District 5 Supply Requisitions, November 18-December 28, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - District 5 Bondings, May 16-25, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - District 5 Finances, $10,000 To Cover Bail Bond, July 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - District 5 Finances, 1937-1947 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Financial Report, October 9, 1937; 1.
    - Disbursment Receipts, February 1, 1941 - September 30, 1943; 2-14.
    - Canadian Congress of Labour Receipt, December 17, 1943; 15.
    - Canadian Congress of Labour Receipt, January 19, 1944; 16.
    - Disbursment Receipt, September 30, 1944; 17.
    - Canadian Congress of Labour Receipt, November 14, 1944; 18.
    - Per Capita Payments, February 16, 1945; 19.
    - Receipts and Disbrusments, November 1945; 20.
    - Budget Report, November 2, 1945; 21.
    - Disbursment Receipt, December 31, 1945; 22.
    - Per Capita and Bonding Expenses, February 22, 1946; 23.
    - Estimated Budget, February 7, 1947; 24.
    - Per Capita Payments, March 24, 1947; 25.
  - District 5 Finances, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Receipts, August 12, 1948 - April 21, 1949; 1-7.
    - Per Capita Payments, December 7, 1949; 8.
    - Receipts, June 21, 1950; 9.
    - Receipts, September 11, 1950; 10.
    - Subsidy Checks, September 12 - November 26, 1951; 11-14.
    - Deposit Slip, November 30, 1951; 15.
    - Deposit Slip, December 4, 1951; 16.
    - Subsidy Check, December 19, 1951; 17.
    - Per Capita and Deposit Slip, January 17, 1952; 18.
    - Per Capita Payments, February 26, 1952; 19.
    - Deposit Slips, March 18 - 20, 1952; 20-22.
    - Check Allocation, March 25, 1952; 23.
    - Per Capita Report, May 21, 1952; 24.
    - Subsidy Check, May 21, 1952; 25.
  - District 5 Finances, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Subsidy Checks, June 24 - October 22, 1952; 1-5.
    - Deposit Slip, November 18, 1952; 6.
    - Subsidy Checks, November 25, 1952 - March 23, 1953; 7-11.
    - Per Capita Reports, March 30, 1953; 12.
    - Subsidy Checks, April 22 - August 21, 1953; 13-17.
    - Payments for Report, August 28, 1953; 18.
    - Subsidy Check, September 2, 1953; 19.
    - Payment for Report, September 29, 1953; 20.
    - Subsidy Checks, October 23 - December 3, 1953; 21-23.
    - Deposit Slip, December 18, 1953; 24.
    - Subsidy Check, December 29, 1953; 25.
  - District 5 Finances, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Subsidy Check, January 13, 1954; 1.
    - Supply Requisition, January 26, 1954; 2.
    - Subsidy Check, April 26, 1954; 3.
    - Deposit Slip, January 18, 1954; 4.
    - Per Capita Payments, January 19, 1954; 5.
    - Subsidy Check, February 11, 1954; 6.
    - Check for Report, February 26, 1954; 7.
    - Subsidy Check, March 24, 1954; 8.
    - Subsidy Check, May 25, 1954; 9.
    - Bonds, June 2, 1954; 10.
    - Check for Report, June 23, 1954; 11.
    - Check Reimbursement, July 27, 1954; 12.
    - Subsidy Check, August 25, 1954; 13.
    - Check for Statements, September 22, 1954; 14.
    - Deposit Slips, October 19 - December 21, 1954; 15-17.
    - Deposit Slips and Per Capita Reports, December 23, 1954; 18.
    - Receipts, January 28, 1955; 19.
    - Per Capita and Deposit Slips, February 18, 1955; 20.
    - Per Capita, Reports, and Deposit Slips, March 18, 1955; 21.
    - Per Capita and Reports, April 6, 1955; 22.
    - Per Capita, Reports, and Deposit Slips, April 18, 1955; 23.
    - Check, May 3, 1955; 24.
    - Per Capita, Reports, and Deposit Slips, May 19, 1955; 25.
  - District 5 Finances, 1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Expenses Account, June 16, 1955; 1.
    - Per Capita, Reports, and Deposit Slips, June 17 - August 22, 1955; 2-4.
    - Per Capita and Deposit Slips, September 19 - November 18, 1955; 5-7.
    - Dues for People's Press, n.d.; 8.
    - Dues, Initiation Books, Unemployment, and Stamps, 9.
  - District 5 Expense Reports, 1944 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - District 5 Per Capita Reports, 1964 - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - District 5 Per Capita Reports, 1970 - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - District 5 Per Capita Reports, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, October 30-31, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, January 15, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, October 27-28, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, May 27, 1945, February 10, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, February 10, 1946, January 26, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, January 25, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, July 10-11, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, September 24-26, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - District 5 Officer's Reports, February 21-22, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - District 5 Officer's Report and Mimeograph Material, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - District 5 Officer's Report and Mimeograph Material, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - District 5 Officer's Report and Mimeograph Material, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, January 28-April 1945 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, January 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, April 27-August 17, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, October 12-13, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, September 24-26, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - District 5 Organizational Reports, October 1952-March 26, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - District 5 Research Reports, April-September 1953 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - District 5 Research Reports, September 1964-October 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - District 5 Research Reports, October 1971 - August 1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - District 5 Organizers Weekly Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Unnamed Organizer, April 17, 1946; 1.
    - Unnamed Organizer, June 22, 1946; 2.
    - G. Harris, July 10, 1946; 3.
    - Doug Fyner, February 5, 1947; 4.
    - John Osborne, February 12, 1947; 5.
    - Unnamed Organizer, April 30, 1947; 6.
    - Unnamed Organizer, May 28, 1947; 7.
  - District 5 RCA Montreal Organization, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Irving Burman to James Matles, June 16, 1938; 1.
    - Matles to Burman, June 21, 1938; 2.
    - Charter Notice, August 18, 1938; 3.
    - Burman to H.B. Prinsky, September 30, 1938; 4.
    - Burman to Matles, October 5, 1938; 5.
  - District 5 Affiliation, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Silby Barrett to All Canadian Congress of Industrial Organizations Affiliates with October 4, 1939, Barrett Letter to Norman McLater, 1.
    - Report, 1939; 2.
  - District 5 Jackson Reports, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Jackson Reports to District Council, August 26, 1939; 1.
    - Jackson Reports to UE Convention, September 4, 1939; 2.
  - District 5 GE Toronto Strike, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Albert Fitzgerald to Canadian GE, June 10, 1941; 1.
    - Fitzgerald to Norman McCarthy, June 10, 1941; 2.
    - Albert Coulthard to C.S. Jackson, June 11, 1941; 3.
    - Bryce Stewart Letter, June 12, 1941; 4.
    - Local 901 to Jackson, June 1941; 5.
    - Local 901 to Canadian GE, June 1941; 6.
    - Local 901 to Norman McCarthy, June 1941; 7.
    - Leo Jandreau to Julius Emspak, June 12, 1941; 8.
    - Milton Seiner to J.J. Ashworth, June 14, 1941; 9.
    - Byrce Stewart to UE, June 14, 1941; 10.
    - James Kennedy to Emspak with Telegrams, June 17, 1941; 11.
    - Letter to Julius Emspak, June 18, 1941; 12.
  - District 5 Canadian Congress of Labour Suspension, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Norman Dowd to CCL Unions, April 3, 1941; 1.
    - Fitzgerald to Norman McCarthy, June 10, 1941; 2.
    - Albert Coulthard to C.S. Jackson, June 11, 1941; 3.
    - CCL Bulletin #10, May 16, 1941; 4.
    - Dowd to Julius Emspak, May 22, 1941; 5.
    - Emspak to Dowd, July 3, 1941; 6.
  - District 5 Jackson Internment, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Dena Jackson to Julius Emspak, July 3, 1941; 1.
    - Albert Smith to Emspak with Lloyd Cole Letter to Herman McCarthy, July 9, 1941; 2.
    - Emspak to Jackson, July 11, 1941; 3.
    - Willard Bliss to Emspak with Newspaper Clippings, July 13, 1941; 4.
    - Smith to Emspak with July 10, 1941, W. Stuart Edwards Letter to Smith, July 14, 1941; 5.
    - Bliss to James Matles, July 19, 1941; 6.
    - Harley DeLong to UE, July 24, 1941; 7.
    - H.R.L. Henry to Joseph Milton, July 24, 1941; 8.
    - R.M. MacDonnell to UE, July 25, 1941; 9.
    - Edwards to Milton, July 26, 1941; 10.
    - Bliss to Matles, August 1, 1941; 11.
    - Clarence Schweyer to Emspak, August 3, 1941; 12.
    - Joseph Curren to UE with Resolution, August 5, 1941; 13.
    - Emspak to Curren, August 8, 1941; 14.
    - J.L. Cohen to Emspak, August 8, 1941; 15.
    - Bliss to Emspak, August 13, 1941; 16.
    - Emspak to Cohen, August 14, 1941; 17.
    - Cohen to Emspak, August 25, 1941; 18.
  - District 5 Jackson Internment, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - George Dodson to UE with Leaflets, September 8, 1941; 1.
    - J.L. Cohen to District 5, September 8, 1941; 2.
    - Williard Bliss to Julius Emspak, September 29, 1941; 3.
    - Dena Jackson to Tom Wright, October 9, 1941; 4.
    - Michael Fitzpatrick to Julius Emspak with October 14, 1941, Fitzpatrick Letters to Ernest Lapointe, Norman McCarthy, Cordell Hull, Loving Christie, and W.L. McKenzie-King, 5.
  - District 5 Jackson Internment, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - J.L. Cohen to Julius Emspak, October 27, 1941; 1.
    - Cohen to UE, October 29, 1941; 2.
    - Cohen to Tom Wright, October 31, 1941; 3.
    - Emspak to Cohen, November 10, 1941; 4.
    - Cohen to James Matles, November 12, 1941; 5.
    - Cohen to Emspak, November 15, 1941; 6.
    - Wright to A.A. Berle, November 24, 1941; 7.
  - District 5 Jackson Internment, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - A.A. Berle Letter, November 27, 1941; 1.
    - J.L. Cohen to James Matles, December 22, 1941; 2.
    - Letter to Poncho, 1941; 3.
    - Cohen to Julius Emspak, January 12, 1942; 4.
    - Cohen to Emspak, February 9, 1942; 5.
    - Willard Bliss to Emspak, February 23, 1942; 6.
  - District 5 Jackson Internment, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Julius Emspak to J.L. Cohen, March 5, 1942; 1.
    - Willard Bliss to Emspak, March 5, 1942; 2.
    - Cohen to Emspak, March 6, 1942; 3.
    - Richard Odgers to Emspak, May 22, 1942; 4.
    - Emspak to Cohen, 1942; 5.
  - District 5 Montreal Organization, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Jack Shaw to James Matles, August 28, 1941; 1.
    - Shaw to Matles, September 4, 1941; 2.
    - Matles to Shaw, September 9, 1941; 3.
  - District 5 UE News List (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Alice Memo to James Matles, April 9, 1943; 1.
    - Alice Memo to Julius Emspak, June 10, 1943; 2.
  - District 5 Canadian Congress of Labour Finances, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Julius Emspak to Pat Conroy, July 9, 1943; 1.
    - Conroy to Emspak, July 20, 1943; 2.
    - Emspak to Conroy, July 23, 1943; 3.
    - Norman Dowd to Emspak, October 12, 1943; 4.
  - District 5 District Council Reports, C.S. Jackson, July 24, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - District 5 District Council Reports, George Harris, July 24, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - District 5 Political Action and Canadian Congress of Labour, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Pat Conroy to Julius Emspak, August 18, 1944; 1.
    - CCL Program for Political Action, 1944; 2.
    - CCL PAC Press Release, 1944; 3.
    - PAC Report, January 28, 1945; 4.
  - District 5 Membership Activities, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Financial and Recreational Report, January 28, 1945; 1.
    - Ruth Young to A.A. Hartwell, February 5, 1945; 2.
  - District 5 World Trade Union Conference, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - C.S. Jackson Report, 1945; 1.
    - Furtherance of the Allied War Effort, 1945; 2.
    - Trade Union Attitude to the Peace Settlement, 1945; 3.
    - Post War Reconstruction, 1945; 4.
  - District 5 World Trade Union Conference, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Basis for World Trade Union Federation, 1945; 1.
    - A Trade Unionist's Views on Belgium and Holland, 1945; 2.
  - District 5 UE Biennial Conference, April 9 - 12, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - District 5 UE Biennial Conference, Hugh Harley Speech, April 9, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - District 5 Post War Economic Plan, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - C.S. Jackson to M.P.'s with Leaflet, September 4, 1945; 1.
    - Albert Fitzgerald to William McKenzie King, September 7, 1945; 2.
    - R.G. Robertson to Fitzgerald, September 11, 1945; 3.
    - Memo to Canadian Government, October 1945; 4.
  - District 5 GE and Westinghouse Strikes, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Memo of Wage Policy Meeting, January 24, 1946; 1.
    - Malcolm Dougan to James Matles, February 19, 1946; 2.
    - Brief, July 30, 1946; 3.
  - District 5 GE and Westinghouse Strikes, Brief to House of Commons, August 1, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - District 5 GE and Westinghouse Strikes, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - William Walsh to James Matles with September 17, 1946, M. Dougan Letter to All Westinghouse Locals, 1.
    - R. Russell to C.S. Jackson, November 21, 1946; 2.
    - Russell to Jackson, November 21, 1946; 3.
  - District 5 Westinghouse Guards Organization, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Kimber & Dubin to David Scribner, July 8, 1946; 1.
    - Scribner to C.L. Dubin, July 12, 1946; 2.
    - Kimber & Dubin to Scribner, July 15, 1946; 3.
  - District 5 Infante Loan, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - James Matles to Joseph Infante, November 5, 1946; 1.
    - Matles to Infante, December 18, 1946; 2.
    - Matles to Infante, December 31, 1946; 3.
    - Matles to Infante, January 9, 1947; 4.
  - District 5 District Council Reports, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Veterans with Mine Mill Strike Resolution, January 26, 1947; 1.
    - Civil and Economic Rights, August 16, 1947; 2.
    - Publicity and Public Report, August 17, 1947; 3.
  - District 5 Joint Board Canada, 1951 - 1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - District 5 Toronto Joint Board, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - John Bettes to Julius Emspak, March 18, 1948; 1.
    - Peter Besch to Ray Klausner, March 29, 1948; 2.
    - Emspak to Bettes, March 30, 1948; 3.
  - District 5 Proctor-Electric Inter-union Rivalry, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Peter Besch to James Matles, January 31, 1951; 1.
    - Matles to James Price, February 2, 1951; 2.
    - Matles to Joseph Infante, February 2, 1951; 3.
    - Matles to Besch, February 2, 1951; 4.
    - Price to Matles, February 5, 1951; 5.
    - Matles to Besch, February 10, 1951; 6.
  - District 5 Osborne Resignation, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Joe Spencer Letter, June 30, 1953; 1.
    - Osborne's Original Letter, July 1953; 2.
    - Spencer Letter, July 4, 1953; 3.
    - Osborne Affair, July 6, 1953; 4.
    - George Harris to UE Officers, July 6, 1953; 5.
    - Harris to Local Secretaries, July 6, 1953; 6.
  - District 5 Wallace Barnes Strike, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Secretary of James Matles to Richard Linsley, July 1, 1953; 1.
    - Nicholas Tomassetti to Matles, July 3, 1953; 2.
    - Matles to Tomassetti, July 8, 1953; 3.
  - District 5 District Council Reports, March 26, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Jobs and Security, March 26, 1955; 1.
    - Atomic Weapons, March 26, 1955; 2.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - District Charter, August 1937; 1.
    - Vice President's Report to General Executive Board, June 10, 1938; 2.
    - Electrical Industry Survey, July 6, 1939; 3.
  - District 5 Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Steelworkers Organizing Committee Lodge Contract, November 3, 1939; 1.
    - H.W. Lothrop to Governor Genera Regarding War Measures Act, November 7, 1939; 2.
    - Letter to J.A. Lunman Regarding Local 510 Negotiation, December 18, 1939; 3.
    - Memo to James Matles Regarding District 5 Officers, January 17, 1940; 4.
    - C.S. Jackson Letter Regarding Unfair Labor Practices and Political Action with Brief, May 28, 1940; 5.
    - Jackson to James Carey, May 30, 1940; 6.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Canadian Congress of Industrial Organizations Committee Minutes, May 23, 1940; 1.
    - Dick Steele Letter Regarding Steelworkers Organizing Committee with June 8, 1940, Steele Letter to Phillip Murray, June 10, 1940; 2.
    - Order in Council 7440 Analysis with Order in Council, January 1941; 3.
    - James Matles to C.S. Jackson Regarding Strikes with June 12, 1941, Bryce Stewart Letter to UE, June 16, 1941; 4.
    - District 5 Organization, August 11, 1941; 5.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Privy Council Order 8253 Regarding War Labor Board, October 24, 1941; 1.
    - Jack Myers to C.S. Jackson Regarding Rustless Iron, January 23, 1943; 3.
    - George Harris to James Matles Regarding Aluminum Workers Inter-union Rivalry with Murray Coterill Letter to C.S. Jackson, May 20, 1943; 3.
  - District 5 War Labor Board Brief, June 3, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - District 5 Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - C.S. Jackson to District 5 Staff Regarding War Labor Board, October 11, 1943; 1.
    - Jackson to District 5 Staff with October 16, 1943, Business Week Excerpt, October 20, 1943; 2.
    - Westinghouse Conference Minutes with April 26, 1944, Thomas Scanlon Letter to Westinghouse Locals, 3.
    - Westinghouse Proposed Contract with June 20, 1944, Jackson Letter to Julius Emspak, 4.
    - Alex Welch Report, August 12, 1944; 5.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - George Burt Speech, October 27, 1944; 1.
    - R. Russell to Julius Emspak, April 3, 1945; 2.
    - Executive Council Canadian Congress of Labour Regarding Political Action with May 22, 1945, C.S. Jackson Letter to Emspak; Defeat Tory Reaction; April 18, 1945, Letter; and April 12, 1945, Burt Letter to All United Auto Workers Unions, April 23, 1945; 3.
  - District 5 Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Allan Haywood to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Canadian Congress of Labour with July 9, 1945, Fitzgerald Letter to C.S. Jackson, 1.
    - A.R. Mosher to CCL Executive Council, July 16, 1945; 2.
    - George Harris to Ottawa Delegation, October 1, 1945; 3.
    - Fitzgerald to C.S. Jackson with January 29, 1946, Haywood Letter to Fitzgerald; January 23, 1946, Norman Dowd Letter to Haywood; and November 21, 1946, C.H. Millard Letter to Mosher, February 6, 1945; 4.
  - District 5 Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - 1946 UE Convention District 5 Report, September 1, 1946; 1.
    - Organizers Weekly Report, December 4, 1946; 2.
    - Report of Canadian Congress of Labour Wage Advisory Committee with January 10, 1947, C.S. Jackson Letter to James Matles; January 9, 1947, Memorandum on Wage Policy; and Memo on Wage Policy, 3.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Ed Matthews to All Westinghouse Locals Regarding White Collar Workers, January 29, 1947; 1.
    - Dave Memo to Julius, February 13, 1947; 2.
    - District 5 Highlights with August 12, 1947, C.S. Jackson to James Matles, August 1947; 3.
    - Trustees Statement, August 13, 1947; 4.
    - James Matles to Ross Cain Regarding Philco Strike, September 4, 1947; 5.
    - Hugh Harley to Cain Regarding Bausch & Lomb Organization, September 12, 1947; 6.
    - Canadian Congress of Labour Resolutions Regarding Foreign Policy with October 8, 1947, C.S. Jackson to Matles, October 7, 1947; 7.
    - John Elliot to D.W. Mather Regarding Landis Machine Organization, October 14, 1947; 8.
  - District 5 Report, Assure to Future Canada's Electric Manufacturing Industry, January 19, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Rogers Majestic Strike Prosectias Bill, July 23, 1948; 1.
    - C.S. Jackson to Staff Regarding Canadian Congress of Labour Mine Mill Expulsion with August 30, 1948, R.H. Carlin Letter to Jackson; September 2, 1948, George Harris Letter to A.R. Mosher; September 3, 1948, UE Press Release; and UE Press Release, 2.
    - Henry Rhodes to Sovereign Potteries Employees Regarding CCL Inter-union Rivalry, November 26, 1948; 3.
    - Contract Provisions, 1948; 4.
  - District 5 Miscellaneous, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Peter Besch to All Delegates Regarding Battery Council with Agenda, May 5, 1949; 1.
    - Julius Emspak to March of Labor, July 1, 1949; 2.
    - District 5 Publicity and Education Report, September 19, 1949; 3.
    - District 5 Resolution Regarding Border Crossing with George Harris Letter to Harry Truman, October 1949; 4.
    - UE GE Presidents to All Canadian Congress of Labour Locals Regarding Factionalism, November 17, 1949; 5.
    - James Matles to Joseph Dermody, March 9, 1950; 6.
    - Audit, May 23, 1950; 7.
  - District 5 Mimeograph Material and Correspondance, 1942 - 1950 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - District 5 Correspondence and Report, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - George Harris to Julius Emspak Regarding World Federation of Trade Unions with Henri Jourdain Article, November 7, 1951; 1.
    - I.A. Legault to Emspak, March 10, 1952; 2.